<Document>
<<<<<<< HEAD
# Glossary

This page contains most slang terms you might encounter on the station and throughout the community !

# In-Character Slang

These are terms you might encounter in-game.

## AOS
Arrest on sight.

## AA
All Access, or an ID which has every access on the station. The captain is the only person who will have this kind of access under normal circumstances.

## Atmos
Short for Atmospherics.

## Atmosian
A term for Atmospheric Technicians, or generally anyone who spends most of their time or is particularly skilled with Atmospherics.

## Bolted
An airlock that will never change states. It will stay permanently open or permanently closed until it is unbolted. Closed and bolted airlocks have solid red lights.

## Borg
Short for cyborgs, player-controlled robots.

## Braindead
Refers to a user who has disconnected from the game. Disconnected users may still reconnect to the server and assume control of their character again.

## Brig
The main area of the security department. This is where prisoners are brought and held for their punishment. The Warden is in charge of the brig's smooth operation.

## Cap
Short for Captain.

## Cargonia
Reference to cargo declaring independence. Against the rules.

## CE
Short for Chief Engineer, the head of the Engineering Department.

## CentComm/Central Command
An administrative agency which oversees the Nanotrasen space station you inhabit.

## CMO
Short for Chief Medical Officer, the head of the Medical Department.

## Crit/Critical
Refers to the health state at which you fall unconscious and unable to move. While in critical, your health slowly decays until you die, unless you happen to get outside assistance.

## Emag
  Refers to the Syndicate cryptographic sequencer. "Emagged" usually refers to airlocks or lockers that are bolted open, but also any other device hacked into by an Emag.

## Emergency Access/EA
  An airlock that can be opened by anyone, even without access or an ID at all. Airlocks that are set to emergency access have blinking yellow lights.

## ERT
An Emergency Response Team. These may be dispatched by Central Command for a number of purposes.

## Flukie
A portmanteau of "Fluke" and "Nukie" used to (usually derogatorily) refer to a team of Nuclear Operatives who fail their objective. May also appear as "Fluke Ops".

## God(s)
An IC term representing a Server Administrator. CentComm is also sometimes used in this manner.

## Greytide/Greyshirt/Tider/Assistant
Typically utilized to refer to a Passenger due to the color of their standard uniform, though this may be used to negatively refer to other crew members (not only passengers) who act unruly or commit various minor crimes.

## HoP
Short for Head of Personnel, head of the Service Department. Can also refer to the HoP's office, where IDs are given or changed.

## HoS
Short for Head of Security, head of the Security Department.

## Insuls
Short for Insulated Gloves. These are the yellow gloves most often worn by Engineers. They are offer complete protection from getting electrocuted from shocked things. Vastily more effective than their budget variety.

## Jani
Short for Janitor.

## KOS
Kill on sight. Someone has commited such a serious crime that they are deemed not even worth arresting.

## Mats
Materials. Usually steel, plastic, plasteel, glass, silver and gold.

## Nanotrasen/NT
Nanotrasen is the company which owns the space station you inhabit.

## Newkie
A portmanteau of "New" and "Nukie" used to refer to an inexperienced player in the role of a Nuclear Operative.

## Nukie
A slang/shorthand term of a Nuclear Operative. May sometimes also appear as "Nuke Op".

## Perma
Short for Permanent Brig. This is for the most serious crime and means that a prisoner will never be released. Most stations have a dedicated, separate area of security for the permanent brig.

## QM
Short for Quartermaster, the head of the Cargo department.

## RD
Short for Research Director, the head of the Science Department.

## Robust
A word used to describe someone who is particularly adept in combat, or endured through a tough fight.

## Salv
Short for Salvage tech.

## Sci
Short for Science.

## Sec
Short for Security.

## Secoff
Short for Security Officer.

## Shift
In-Character way to refer to rounds.

## Singulo
A shortening of the Singularity Engine. A Singulo can create infinite power for the station but is very dangerous.

## Singuloose
A Singularity that has grown too much and breached its containment. It will rip through the station causing massive damage.

## Spacing
An event which causes an area to lose air pressure, i.e. a hull breach.

## Spess
An intentional mis-spelling of "Space", sometimes used as a portmanteau of "space" and "mess". May also appear in words such as "Spessmen".

## SSD
Short for Sudden Sleep Disorder or Space Sleep Disorder. This is an in-character way to refer to a player who has disconnected and is no longer responding.

## Syndie/Syndi/Syndicate
A catch-all reference to anyone employed by the Syndicate. This ranges from (suspected) Syndicate Agents to Nuclear Operatives.

## TC
A telecrystal, which is a currency used by Syndicate Agents to purchase restricted contraband such as weapons and other illegal equipment.

## Wardenloose
A joke term referencing a Singuloose. A wardenloose is when the Warden is seen outside of the brig.

## Xenoarchaeology
Study of artifacts, usually performed by science.

# Out-Of-Character Slang

These are terms you should only be using in OOC chat or outside the game.

## Admeme
An event hosted or caused by an admin.

## AHelp/Admin Help
A relay used to report rulebreaking behavior or other issues to administrators.

## Antag
Short for Antagonists, which are specifically picked individuals designed to drive the round into chaos.

## Bwoink
The noise made when an admin-help is received. Pray this isn't a ban.

## Ick Ock
A phrase usually shouted in OOC when somebody reveals IC current round information, or "in-character, out-of-character".

## LOOC/OOC
Local out-of-character and (global) out-of-character respectively. They are text channels that allow players to talk to other players outside of roleplay. LOOC is enabled during rounds, while OOC is typically only on after the round ends.

## LRP
Low Roleplay. Servers marked LRP typically have relaxed roleplaying rules.

## MRP
Medium Roleplay. Servers marked MRP usually have a decent basis of roleplaying rules and generally require players to act as their character would realistically in a given situation. Less leeway is afforded to behavior such as openly defying Security or your boss.

## HRP
High Roleplay. Servers marked HRP generally have extensive rules on what is and is not constituted while playing a character. You are generally required to act as your character would, have a character backstory, and follow protocol on the station. Some HRP servers may create their own lore or settings to further facilitate the type of server they wish to host.

## Self-Antag
A term for a player who engages in antagonist-like activity without actually being an antagonist. This encompasses a wide variety of behavior, but is typically used to describe annoying behavior or actions which are greatly detrimental to other players for no purpose. Self-antagonism is a bannable offense. Sometimes used in IC. DO NOT DO THIS.

## Upstream
The baseline version of the game. Any changes to Upstream will "flow" down to all other forks of the game. All official Wizard's Den servers work off of Upstream.

## Validhunter
A player who hunts down "valids", as in people that are valid to kill, even though this person isn't security.
=======
# Glossário

Esta página contém a maioria dos termos de gíria que você pode encontrar na estação e em toda a comunidade!

# Gírias In-Character

Estes são termos que você pode encontrar no jogo.

## AOS
Prisões à vista.

## AA
Acesso Total, ou um ID que possui todos os acessos na estação. O capitão é a única pessoa que terá esse tipo de acesso sob circunstâncias normais.

## Atmos
Abreviação de Atmosférica.

## Atmosiano
Termo usado para Técnicos Atmosféricos, ou, em geral, qualquer pessoa que passe a maior parte do tempo ou seja particularmente habilidosa com Atmosféricas.

## Parafusado
Uma comporta que nunca mudará de estado. Ela ficará permanentemente aberta ou permanentemente fechada até ser desparafusada. Comportas fechadas e parafusadas têm luzes vermelhas sólidas.

## Borg
Abreviação de ciborgues, robôs controlados por jogadores.

## Braindead
Refere-se a um usuário que desconectou do jogo. Usuários desconectados ainda podem reconectar ao servidor e retomar o controle de seu personagem.

## Brig
A principal área do departamento de segurança. Aqui é onde os prisioneiros são levados e mantidos para sua punição. O Warden é responsável pela operação tranquila do brig.

## Cap
Abreviação de Capitão.

## Cargônia
Referência à carga declarando independência. Contra as regras.

## CE
Abreviação de Chefe de Engenharia, o chefe do Departamento de Engenharia.

## CentComm/Comando Central
Uma agência administrativa que supervisiona a estação espacial Nanotrasen que você habita.

## CMO
Abreviação de Chefe Médico, o chefe do Departamento Médico.

## Crit/Critico
Refere-se ao estado de saúde em que você desmaia e fica incapaz de se mover. Quando em crítico, sua saúde diminui lentamente até você morrer, a menos que receba ajuda externa.

## Emag
Refere-se ao sequenciador criptográfico da Syndicate. "Emagged" geralmente se refere a comportas ou armários que estão bolted abertos, mas também qualquer outro dispositivo hackeado por um Emag.

## Acesso de Emergência/EA
Uma comporta que pode ser aberta por qualquer um, mesmo sem acesso ou ID. Comportas com acesso de emergência têm luzes amarelas piscando.

## ERT
Equipe de Resposta de Emergência. Podem ser despachados pelo Comando Central para diversos fins.

## Flukie
Um termo que mistura "Fluke" e "Nukie" usado para (geralmente de forma depreciativa) se referir a uma equipe de Operativos Nucleares que falharam em seu objetivo. Pode também aparecer como "Fluke Ops".

## Deus(es)
Um termo IC que representa um Administrador de Servidor. CentComm também pode ser usado dessa maneira.

## Greytide/Camiseta Cinza/Tider/Assistente
Normalmente utilizado para se referir a um Passageiro devido à cor do uniforme padrão, embora também possa ser usado de forma negativa para se referir a outros membros da tripulação (não apenas passageiros) que agem de maneira indisciplinada ou cometem crimes menores.

## HoP
Abreviação de Chefe de Pessoal, chefe do Departamento de Serviço. Também pode se referir ao escritório do HoP, onde IDs são dados ou alterados.

## HoS
Abreviação de Chefe de Segurança, chefe do Departamento de Segurança.

## Insuls
Abreviação de Luvas Isolantes. São as luvas amarelas frequentemente usadas por Engenheiros. Elas oferecem proteção completa contra choques elétricos. Muito mais eficazes do que suas versões mais baratas.

## Jani
Abreviação de Zelador.

## KOS
Matar à vista. Alguém cometeu um crime tão grave que é considerado não digno nem de ser preso.

## Mats
Materiais. Normalmente aço, plástico, plastel, vidro, prata e ouro.

## Nanotrasen/NT
Nanotrasen é a empresa que possui a estação espacial que você habita.

## Newkie
Uma mistura de "New" e "Nukie" usada para se referir a um jogador inexperiente no papel de Operativo Nuclear.

## Nukie
Uma gíria/abreviação para Operativo Nuclear. Também pode aparecer como "Nuke Op".

## Perma
Abreviação de Brig Permanente. Este é para o crime mais grave e significa que o prisioneiro nunca será libertado. A maioria das estações tem uma área separada e dedicada de segurança para o brig permanente.

## QM
Abreviação de Quartermaster, o chefe do departamento de Carga.

## RD
Abreviação de Diretor de Pesquisa, o chefe do Departamento de Ciência.

## Robust
Uma palavra usada para descrever alguém que é particularmente habilidoso em combate, ou que sobreviveu a uma luta difícil.

## Salv
Abreviação de Técnico de Salvamento.

## Sci
Abreviação de Ciência.

## Sec
Abreviação de Segurança.

## Secoff
Abreviação de Oficial de Segurança.

## Shift
Forma in-game de se referir às rodadas.

## Singulo
Uma abreviação de Singularity Engine. Um Singulo pode gerar energia infinita para a estação, mas é muito perigoso.

## Singuloose
Uma Singularity que cresceu demais e rompeu sua contenção. Ela irá destruir a estação causando danos massivos.

## Spacing
Um evento que faz uma área perder a pressão do ar, ou seja, uma ruptura no casco.

## Spess
Uma grafia intencionalmente errada de "Space" (espaço), às vezes usada como uma junção de "space" e "mess". Também pode aparecer em palavras como "Spessmen".

## SSD
Abreviação de Sudden Sleep Disorder ou Space Sleep Disorder. Esta é uma forma de se referir, no personagem, a um jogador que se desconectou e não está mais respondendo.

## Syndie/Syndi/Syndicate
Uma referência geral a qualquer pessoa empregada pelo Syndicate. Isso inclui desde (suspeitos) Agentes do Syndicate até Operativos Nucleares.

## TC
Um telecristal, que é uma moeda usada por Agentes do Syndicate para comprar contrabando restrito, como armas e outros equipamentos ilegais.

## Wardenloose
Um termo de piada referindo-se a um Singuloose. Um wardenloose ocorre quando o Warden é visto fora da brig.

## Xenoarchaeology
Estudo de artefatos, geralmente realizado pela ciência.

# Gírias Fora-de-Personagem

Esses são termos que você deve usar apenas no chat OOC ou fora do jogo.

## Admeme
Um evento hospedado ou causado por um administrador.

## AHelp/Admin Help
Um meio de comunicação utilizado para relatar comportamentos que quebram as regras ou outros problemas para os administradores.

## Antag
Abreviação de Antagonistas, indivíduos escolhidos especificamente para levar a rodada ao caos.

## Bwoink
O som feito quando um admin-help é recebido. Reze para que isso não seja um banimento.

## Ick Ock
Uma frase geralmente gritada em OOC quando alguém revela informações da rodada atual IC, ou "in-character, out-of-character".

## LOOC/OOC
Local out-of-character e (global) out-of-character, respectivamente. São canais de texto que permitem que os jogadores conversem com outros jogadores fora do roleplay. LOOC está ativado durante as rodadas, enquanto OOC geralmente é apenas após a rodada terminar.

## LRP
Low Roleplay. Servidores marcados como LRP geralmente têm regras de roleplay mais relaxadas.

## MRP
Medium Roleplay. Servidores marcados como MRP geralmente têm uma base decente de regras de roleplay e geralmente exigem que os jogadores ajam como seus personagens agiriam realisticamente em uma situação dada. Menos liberdade é dada para comportamentos como desafiar abertamente a segurança ou seu chefe.

## HRP
High Roleplay. Servidores marcados como HRP geralmente têm regras extensas sobre o que é e o que não é constituído enquanto se joga um personagem. Normalmente, você é obrigado a agir como seu personagem agiria, ter uma história de fundo do personagem e seguir os protocolos da estação. Alguns servidores HRP podem criar sua própria lore ou configurações para facilitar o tipo de servidor que desejam hospedar.

## Self-Antag
Um termo para um jogador que se envolve em atividades de antagonista sem realmente ser um antagonista. Isso abrange uma ampla variedade de comportamentos, mas geralmente é usado para descrever comportamentos irritantes ou ações que são extremamente prejudiciais a outros jogadores sem propósito. A auto-antagonismo é uma ofensa passível de banimento. Às vezes é usado IC. NÃO FAÇA ISSO.

## Upstream
A versão base do jogo. Quaisquer alterações no Upstream "fluem" para todas as outras versões do jogo. Todos os servidores oficiais do Wizard's Den funcionam a partir do Upstream.

## Validhunter
Um jogador que caça "validos", ou seja, pessoas que são válidas para matar, mesmo que essa pessoa não seja segurança.
>>>>>>> fire

</Document>
