<Document>
<<<<<<< HEAD
# Station and Shifts

Every round of SS14 is a [bold]self-contained shift[/bold] that takes place on one of many different stations.

Rounds typically last from [color=cyan]45 to 90 minutes[/color], but players are free to leave and join at any point during a round.

## Shuttle Terminal
If you join in the middle of a shift, you will likely spawn on the [color=lime]shuttle terminal[/color].
Here you can grab drinks, converse with other players, and wait for the shuttle to take you to the station.

Screens on the walls will give you an ETA for the shuttle.
When it arrives, simply walk on to be transported to the station.

Make sure to stay inside the terminal and to not stand in the shuttle landing zone. [color=#EB2D3A][bold]You can be crushed by shuttles flying in[/bold][/color]

## Navigation
Every station has a wide variety of locations to visit.
These range from specific departments where work happens to common areas where you can relax and chat with others.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="StationMap"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SignDirectionalDorms" Caption="Directional Signs"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SignBridge" Caption="Marker Signs"/>
</Box>

[color=cyan]Station maps[/color] give you an overview of the entire station with colored markers denoting locations of different things.
Regular [color=cyan]signs[/color] on walls can point you to different departments.

## Leaving the Station
At the end of the shift [color=gray](barring a [color=red][bold]nuclear disaster[/bold][/color])[/color], you will leave the station via the [color=lime]evac shuttle[/color].
When it's called, an announcement will play on the station alerting the crew and signaling its [color=cyan]arrival in 10 minutes.[/color]
Once it arrives, you'll need to make your way over to it, board it, and then survive the trip to [bold]Central Command[/bold].

The round doesn't officially end until you reach [bold]Central Command[/bold]
=======
# Estação e Turnos

Cada rodada de SS14 é um [bold]turno autocontido[/bold] que ocorre em uma das diversas estações.

As rodadas normalmente duram de [color=cyan]45 a 90 minutos[/color], mas os jogadores estão livres para sair e entrar a qualquer momento durante a rodada.

## Terminal de Shuttle
Se você entrar no meio de um turno, provavelmente aparecerá no [color=lime]terminal de shuttle[/color].
Aqui você pode pegar bebidas, conversar com outros jogadores e esperar o shuttle para levá-lo até a estação.

As telas nas paredes mostrarão o ETA do shuttle.
Quando ele chegar, basta entrar para ser transportado até a estação.

Certifique-se de ficar dentro do terminal e não ficar na zona de pouso do shuttle. [color=#EB2D3A][bold]Você pode ser esmagado pelos shuttles que estão pousando[/bold][/color].

## Navegação
Cada estação tem uma grande variedade de locais a serem visitados.
Esses locais variam desde departamentos específicos onde o trabalho acontece até áreas comuns onde você pode relaxar e conversar com outras pessoas.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="StationMap"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SignDirectionalDorms" Caption="Placas de Direção"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SignBridge" Caption="Placas de Localização"/>
</Box>

Os [color=cyan]mapas da estação[/color] fornecem uma visão geral de toda a estação, com marcadores coloridos indicando os locais de diferentes coisas.
Placas [color=cyan]regulares[/color] nas paredes podem direcioná-lo para diferentes departamentos.

## Deixando a Estação
Ao final do turno [color=gray](exceto em caso de [color=red][bold]desastre nuclear[/bold][/color])[/color], você deixará a estação através do [color=lime]shuttle de evacuação[/color].
Quando for chamado, um anúncio será feito na estação alertando a tripulação e sinalizando sua [color=cyan]chegada em 10 minutos.[/color]
Quando ele chegar, você precisará ir até ele, embarcar e sobreviver à viagem até o [bold]Comando Central[/bold].

A rodada não termina oficialmente até que você chegue ao [bold]Comando Central[/bold].
>>>>>>> fire

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="CryogenicSleepUnit"/>
</Box>

<<<<<<< HEAD
If you need to leave a round early, you can do so through a [color=lime]cryogenic sleep unit[/color].
Simply going inside and leaving the game will store your belongings and ensure that they are not stolen or misused.

## More Info
Learning the controls? [textlink="Click here to read about the different controls" link="Controls"]

Don't know how to perform a job? [textlink="Click here to jump to a list of departments" link="Jobs"]

Keep dying? [textlink="Click here to see a survival guide" link="Survival"]
=======
Se precisar sair de uma rodada mais cedo, você pode fazer isso através de uma [color=lime]unidade de sono criogênico[/color].
Basta entrar e sair do jogo que seus pertences serão armazenados e garantirão que não sejam roubados ou usados indevidamente.

## Mais Informações
Aprendendo os controles? [textlink="Clique aqui para ler sobre os diferentes controles" link="Controls"]

Não sabe como realizar um trabalho? [textlink="Clique aqui para pular para uma lista de departamentos" link="Jobs"]

Morrendo muito? [textlink="Clique aqui para ver um guia de sobrevivência" link="Survival"]
>>>>>>> fire

</Document>
