<Document>
<<<<<<< HEAD
  # Zombies

  <Box>
    [color=#999999][italic]"They're coming to get you, Barbara!"[/italic][/color]
=======
  # Zumbis

  <Box>
    [color=#999999][italic]"Eles estão vindo te pegar, Barbara!"[/italic][/color]
>>>>>>> fire
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="SignBiohazard" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

<<<<<<< HEAD
  Zombies are conversion antagonists that infect all beings that they bite with [color=#7e916e]Romerol[/color], a deadly, contagious virus that can easily spread if not contained.
=======
  Os zumbis são antagonistas de conversão que infectam todos os seres que mordem com [color=#7e916e]Romerol[/color], um vírus mortal e contagioso que pode se espalhar facilmente se não for contido.
>>>>>>> fire

  <Box>
    <GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="Romerol"/>
  </Box>

<<<<<<< HEAD
  ## Initial Infected
  You are patient zero. You have [color=#7e916e]Romerol[/color] coursing through your veins and you have a grand desire to share it with every single flesh being you see.

  Upon learning of your infection, [italic]all bets are off[/italic]. You have only so much time before you turn, and you want to [bold]maximize your chances of taking over the station.[/bold]
  Use this time to prepare weapons, gear, and traps. [italic]Space Law means nothing to you now.[/italic]

  ## Transmission
  Zombies only know how to shamble, bite and throw themselves against barricades. Their bite [bold]may not always transmit [color=#7e916e]Romerol[/color][/bold] through heavy layers of clothing, but it'll definitely hurt.

  The undead can also chomp on a crit or dead body to [bold]instantly convert[/bold] it to a zombie.

  ## Zombie Attributes
  A zombie can be identified by dark green skin, red eyes, slow movement, rotting smell, and lack of motor functions. They'll drop their headset and gloves upon turning, and cuffs don't work against their vicious bite.

  Zombies are known for their [bold]resilience to slashes, bruises, poison and cold.[/bold] They can survive in a vacuum and do not require food, water, air, or sleep. The undead do, however, [italic]take increased burn and shock damage.[/italic]

  ## Survival
  When the infection sweeps and [color=#cb0000]Security[/color] falls, it's up to the [bold]survivors[/bold] to try and make it to Central Command.

  [bold]Constructing barricades[/bold] around departments or [bold]bolting doors[/bold] can buy enough time to make weapons, save lives or make a plan.

  Remember that when it really hits the fan, [italic]you've gotta do what you gotta do[/italic], as long as it's not at the expense of fellow survivors. Scavenge what you need from those who haven't made it.

  ## Cure
  [bold]Those who are already undead can only be cured by [color=red]death.[/color][/bold]

  If you're infected but not zombified yet, using [color=#86caf7]Ambuzol[/color] will cure you but won't prevent re-infection. [color=#1274b5]Ambuzol Plus[/color] will cure and prevent re-infection only while alive.
=======
  ## Iniciado Infectado
  Você é o paciente zero. Você tem [color=#7e916e]Romerol[/color] correndo pelas suas veias e um grande desejo de compartilhá-lo com todos os seres de carne que você vê.

  Ao descobrir sua infecção, [italic]não há mais volta[/italic]. Você tem pouco tempo antes de se transformar, e deseja [bold]maximizar suas chances de tomar conta da estação.[/bold]
  Use esse tempo para preparar armas, equipamentos e armadilhas. [italic]A Lei Espacial não significa nada para você agora.[/italic]

  ## Transmissão
  Os zumbis só sabem como arrastar-se, morder e se jogar contra barricadas. Sua mordida [bold]pode não transmitir [color=#7e916e]Romerol[/color] através de camadas pesadas de roupa[/bold], mas definitivamente vai doer.

  Os mortos-vivos também podem morder um corpo em estado crítico ou morto para [bold]converter instantaneamente[/bold] esse corpo em um zumbi.

  ## Atributos do Zumbi
  Um zumbi pode ser identificado pela pele verde escura, olhos vermelhos, movimento lento, cheiro de decomposição e falta de funções motoras. Eles largam seus fones de ouvido e luvas ao se transformar, e algemas não funcionam contra sua mordida feroz.

  Os zumbis são conhecidos por sua [bold]resiliência a cortes, hematomas, veneno e frio.[/bold] Eles podem sobreviver no vácuo e não precisam de comida, água, ar ou sono. Os mortos-vivos, no entanto, [italic]sofrem mais dano de queimaduras e choques.[/italic]

  ## Sobrevivência
  Quando a infecção se espalha e [color=#cb0000]a Segurança[/color] cai, cabe aos [bold]sobreviventes[/bold] tentar chegar ao Comando Central.

  [bold]Construir barricadas[/bold] ao redor dos departamentos ou [bold]trancar portas[/bold] pode comprar tempo suficiente para fabricar armas, salvar vidas ou fazer um plano.

  Lembre-se de que quando as coisas realmente saem do controle, [italic]você tem que fazer o que for necessário[/italic], desde que não seja às custas de outros sobreviventes. Saqueie o que precisar daqueles que não conseguiram sobreviver.

  ## Cura
  [bold]Aqueles que já estão mortos-vivos só podem ser curados por [color=red]morte.[/color][/bold]

  Se você está infectado mas ainda não se transformou em zumbi, usar [color=#86caf7]Ambuzol[/color] irá curá-lo, mas não impedirá a reinfecção. [color=#1274b5]Ambuzol Plus[/color] irá curar e prevenir a reinfecção apenas enquanto estiver vivo.
>>>>>>> fire

  <Box>
    <GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="Ambuzol"/>
  </Box>
  <Box>
    <GuideReagentEmbed Reagent="AmbuzolPlus"/>
  </Box>

</Document>
